Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
Today we're bringing you part two of another great lesson that we had.
今天我们为大家带来之前那节精彩课程的第二部分。
Yes, new guy in town.
是的，新来的家伙。
The new guy in town.
新来的家伙。
Part two.
第二部分。
Kind of a creepy story.
有点毛骨悚然的故事。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, and this one is also a little bit strange, a little bit weird.
嗯，这个也有点奇怪，有点诡异。
Yeah, unusual outcome, unusual ending.
对，不寻常的结果，不寻常的结局。
But it has to do a lot with invitations.
但这和邀请有很大关系。
That's right.
没错。
An invitation is when you ask somebody to do something with you.
邀请就是你请别人和你一起做某事。
Right.
对。
A dinner invitation.
晚餐邀请。
So we're going to be talking about invitations and inviting people to do things.
所以我们要讨论邀请和邀请别人做事。
Okay.
好的。
Well, with that, let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
那么，让我们第一次听对话。
Oh, Arman, thank you for such a thoughtful invitation.
哦，Arman，谢谢你这么体贴的邀请。
It's really very nice of you to invite us over for dinner.
你邀请我们过来吃晚饭真是太好了。
Don't you think so, Ellen?
你不觉得吗，Ellen？
Oh, yes, of course.
哦，是的，当然。
We'd love to come over.
我们很乐意过来。
Can I bring anything?
我需要带点什么吗？
No, don't worry about it.
不用，别担心。
I'll take care of everything.
我会搞定一切。
I'll see you tonight.
今晚见。
Come with an appetite.
带着胃口来。
I know I will.
我知道我会的。
I don't want to go over to his place for dinner.
我不想去他家吃晚饭。
He gives me the creeps.
他让我起鸡皮疙瘩。
Why on earth did you accept?
你到底为什么答应了？
Oh, come on, Ellen.
哦，得了吧，Ellen。
It'll be nice to get to know him.
认识一下他会很好的。
Besides, he's new to the neighborhood.
再说，他是新搬来的邻居。
He's a bit of a creep.
他有点怪。
他有点令人毛骨悚然。
He's a bit of a creep.
Ladies!
女士们！
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你们的光临。
You look delicious.
你看起来很好吃。
I mean beautiful.
我是说很漂亮。
Please come in.
请进。
Oh, Arlond, you are too kind.
哦，阿隆德，你太客气了。
How did I get myself into this?
我怎么把自己搞成这样了？
Wow, I'm really anxious to see what happens in this dinner party.
哇，我真的很想知道这个晚宴上会发生什么。
Yeah, I guess we'll have to stay tuned and find out.
是啊，我想我们得继续关注才能知道。
For part three.
第三部分。
Yeah.
嗯。
All right, well, we have some really great vocabulary, so I guess we can start with language
好了，我们有一些很棒的词汇，所以我想我们可以从语言
takeaway.
要点开始。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, on language takeaway today, we have three great words.
好的，今天的语言要点，我们有三个很棒的词。
Erika, why don't you start us off with the first one?
Erika，你先开始第一个吧？
The first word is thoughtful.
第一个词是 thoughtful。
Thoughtful.
Thoughtful。
So, when you're thoughtful, you're kind, right?
所以，当你 thoughtful 时，你很友善，对吧？
You're kind, you're considerate to other people.
你很友善，为他人着想。
You think about what the other person would like.
你会考虑对方喜欢什么。
Right.
对。
And you do that thing.
然后你就那么做了。
It's so thoughtful of you.
你真是太体贴了。
Yeah.
嗯。
Our second phrase, give me the creeps.
我们的第二个短语，give me the creeps。
Give me the creeps.
Give me the creeps。
This is kind of a funny phrase, but I think if we listen to some examples, we'll understand
这个短语有点搞笑，但我想如果我们听一些例子，就会明白了。
the meaning.
意思。
Example one.
例子一。
Horror movies give me the creeps.
恐怖电影让我毛骨悚然。
Example two.
例子二。
Stop it.
别这样。
You're giving me the creeps.
你让我起鸡皮疙瘩了。
Example three.
例子三。
I saw this really scary clown.
我看到一个非常可怕的小丑。
It gave me the creeps.
它让我毛骨悚然。
So I can see this one means to make me feel uncomfortable.
所以我能看出这个短语的意思是让我感到不舒服。
Right.
对。
It makes me feel like scared.
它让我感到害怕。
Yeah, scared.
是的，害怕。
Also, gives me the creeps.
还有，让我毛骨悚然。
And our last phrase for language takeaway, rope me into.
我们语言摘录的最后一个短语是“rope me into”。
Rope me into something.
说服我做某事。
So if you rope me into something, it's...
所以如果你说服我做某事，那就是……
It's like you convince me to do something that I don't really want to do.
就像你说服我去做一件我并不真正想做的事。
Right.
对。
So I roped you into lending me your car.
所以我说服你把车借给我。
Yes.
是的。
It was a bad idea.
那是个坏主意。
That was a bad idea.
And you roped me into going out for beers after work.
而你说服我下班后出去喝啤酒。
Yeah, that was a great idea.
是啊，那是个好主意。
All right, so rope me into, convince.
好了，所以“rope me into”就是说服。
Yeah.
是的。
All righty.
好的。
So I guess we could listen to our dialogue again.
我想我们可以再听一遍对话。
This time a little bit slower and you'll be able to understand the language a little bit
这次慢一点，你就能更清楚地理解语言了。
more clearly.
更清楚。
Oh, Armand, thank you for such a thoughtful invitation.
哦，阿曼德，谢谢你这么体贴的邀请。
It's really very nice of you to invite us over for dinner.
你邀请我们来吃晚饭真是太好了。
Don't you think so, Ellen?
你不觉得吗，艾伦？
Oh, yes, of course.
哦，是的，当然。
We'd love to come over.
我们很乐意来。
Can I bring anything?
我需要带点什么吗？
No, don't worry about it.
不用，别担心。
I'll take care of everything.
我会搞定一切的。
I'll see you tonight.
今晚见。
Come with an appetite.
带着胃口来。
I know I will.
我知道我会的。
I don't want to go over to his place for dinner.
我不想去他家吃晚饭。
He gives me the creeps.
他让我毛骨悚然。
Why on earth did you accept?
你到底为什么答应了？
Oh, come on, Ellen.
哦，别这样，艾伦。
It would be nice to get to know him.
认识一下他也挺好的。
Besides, he's new to the neighborhood and it would be rude to decline his invitation.
再说，他是新搬来的邻居，拒绝他的邀请不礼貌。
I guess so.
我想是吧。
You always rope me into things like this.
你总是把我拉进这种事。
Ladies, thank you for coming.
女士们，谢谢你们的光临。
You look delicious.
你看起来很好吃。
I mean, beautiful.
我是说，很漂亮。
Please come in.
请进。
Come in.
进来吧。
Oh, Armand, you are too kind.
哦，阿曼德，你太客气了。
How did I get myself into this?
我怎么就卷进来了？
Well, I guess that's a lot more clear and with that, we can start putting it together
嗯，我想这清楚多了，这样我们就可以开始把它组合起来
today.
今天。
Putting it together.
组合起来。
Today we've got three words and phrases that we want to show you how you can put together
今天我们有三个单词和短语，想展示给你们如何组合
and use differently.
并不同地使用。
The first one is appetite.
第一个是 appetite。
Appetite.
Appetite。
So, appetite is like a strong desire for food, right?
所以，appetite 就像是对食物的强烈欲望，对吧？
Right.
对。
An appetite.
An appetite。
We've got some examples that show you how to use this phrase.
我们有一些例子展示如何使用这个短语。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
Dinner smells so good.
晚餐闻起来真香。
It's giving me an appetite.
让我有了胃口。
Example two.
例子二。
You're sure eating a lot.
你吃得真多。
You must have a big appetite.
你胃口一定很好。
Example three.
例子三。
I'm getting sick.
我生病了。
I have a fever and I've lost my appetite.
我发烧了，而且没有胃口。
Okay, so we saw some great examples of appetite.
好的，我们看到了几个关于“胃口”的好例子。
You can lose your appetite.
你可以说“没有胃口”。
That's right.
没错。
You have a big appetite.
“胃口很大”。
A small appetite.
“胃口小”。
A healthy appetite.
“胃口好”。
Right.
对。
So, appetite just means... a desire for food.
所以，“胃口”就是指……对食物的欲望。
A hunger for food.
对食物的渴望。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
很好。
What's our second phrase for today?
我们今天的第二个短语是什么？
Get to know someone.
认识某人。
Get to know.
认识。
So when you get to know someone is you talk to them and you find out what they do.
当你“认识”某人时，就是和他们交谈，了解他们做什么。
Yeah.
是的。
You get more familiar with them.
你对他们更熟悉了。
More familiar, right?
更熟悉了，对吧？
For example, we can say, I got to know her in Spanish class and she's a really nice person.
例如，我们可以说，我在西班牙语课上认识了她，她人很好。
Yeah.
是的。
Or you can say, Armand, Ellen, and Doris got to know each other at a dinner party.
或者你可以说，阿曼德、艾伦和多丽丝在一次晚宴上认识了彼此。
Right.
对。
Or you can say, if you get to know me, you'll see that I'm not a bad guy.
或者你可以说，如果你了解我，你会发现我不是坏人。
Yeah.
是的。
That's true.
确实。
Okay.
好的。
Get to know.
认识。
And our third phrase is, why on earth?
我们的第三个短语是，“到底为什么？”
Why on earth?
到底为什么？
This is like a saying.
这像是一个说法。
Yeah.
是的。
Expression.
表达方式。
You can use it in a lot of different ways.
你可以在很多不同的场合使用它。
So we've got some examples for you.
我们给你准备了一些例子。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
Where on earth is my phone?
我的手机到底在哪儿？
Example two.
例子二。
How on earth did you learn English in one month?
你到底是怎么在一个月内学会英语的？
Example three.
例子三。
What on earth is it?
这到底是什么东西？
So when you ask a question with on earth, so why on earth, how on earth, what on earth,
所以当你用 on earth 提问时，比如 why on earth、how on earth、what on earth，
it's like you're showing a lot of surprise.
就像是在表达你非常惊讶。
Okay.
好的。
Great stuff.
太棒了。
So let's just listen to our dialogue a third time.
那我们再听一遍对话吧。
Oh, Armand, thank you for such a thoughtful invitation.
哦，阿曼德，谢谢你这么贴心的邀请。
It's really very nice of you to invite us over for dinner.
你邀请我们过来吃晚饭真是太好了。
Don't you think so, Ellen?
你不觉得吗，艾伦？
Oh, yes, of course.
哦，是的，当然。
We'd love to come over.
我们很乐意过来。
Can I bring anything?
我需要带点什么吗？
No.
不用。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
I'll take care of everything.
我会搞定一切的。
I'll see you tonight.
今晚见。
Come with an appetite.
留着胃口来。
I know I will.
我知道我会的。
I don't want to go over to his place for dinner.
我不想去他家吃晚饭。
He gives me the creeps.
他让我起鸡皮疙瘩。
Why on earth did you accept?
你到底为什么要答应？
Come on, Ellen.
拜托，艾伦。
It'll be nice to get to know him.
认识一下他也挺好的。
Besides, he's new to the neighborhood.
再说，他是新搬来的邻居。
He'll be rude to decline his invitation.
拒绝他的邀请会很失礼。
I guess so.
我想是吧。
You always wrote me into things like this.
你总是把我拖进这种事情里。
Ladies.
女士们。
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你们的光临。
You look delicious.
你看起来很好吃。
I mean, beautiful.
我是说，很漂亮。
Please come in.
请进。
Oh, Arlond, you are too kind.
哦，阿隆德，你太客气了。
How did I get myself into this?
我怎么把自己搞成这样了？
We want to know what you think happens next.
我们想知道你觉得接下来会发生什么。
Yes, what happens in this dialogue next.
是的，这个对话接下来会发生什么。
So we want you to send us your idea of what happens next and we're going to choose the
所以我们希望你把接下来发生的故事想法发给我们，我们会选出
best one.
最好的一个。
That's right.
没错。
Marco and I will choose the best continuation of the story and we'll use that in part three
马可和我会选出故事的最佳续写，然后我们会把它用在《小镇新人》的第三部分。
of The New Guy in Town.
《小镇新人》的第三部分。
That's right.
没错。
So you can give it any direction you want.
所以你可以朝任何方向发挥。
That's right.
没错。
And of course, we'll publish the name of the author with the lesson.
当然，我们会把作者的名字和课程一起发布。
Yes.
是的。
I'm really anxious to see what ideas come up and how we can end this dialogue.
我真的很期待看到大家会有什么想法，以及我们如何结束这个对话。
I know.
我知道。
We've got a lot of really creative users out there.
我们有很多非常有创意的用户。
So I'm really looking forward to this.
所以我真的很期待。
That's right.
没错。
So be sure to send us your ideas, either a private message or you can post it on the
所以一定要把你的想法发给我们，可以私信，也可以发在这节课的
comment section of this lesson.
评论区。
And any other questions or doubts, go to EnglishPod.com and you can leave them there.
如果有其他问题或疑问，请访问EnglishPod.com，你可以在那里留言。
Yes.
是的。
Marco and I are always happy to answer your questions.
马可和我总是很乐意回答你们的问题。
Okay, folks.
好了，各位。
So until then, it's goodbye.
那么，下次再见。